♪～
MAIN BATTLE REGIMENT
COMMANDER-IN-CHIEF: GAARA
（テンテン）えっと　私たちの隊長って
どの人なんですか？
So... Who's our captain?
FIRST COMPANY:
MID-RANGE BATTLE UNIT
（チョウザ）あそこのだるそうに
してる人だよ。
That spacey looking
guy over there.
FIRST COMPANY CAPTAIN:
DARUI
I-I'm starting to feel nervous.
（ヒナタ）なんか　緊張してきました。
SECOND COMPANY:
CLOSE-RANGE BATTLE UNIT
（カルイ）フン　戦争なんて余裕余裕。
In war, stay calm...
and composed!
（黒ツチ）んだよ！　親父が隊長かよ！
Hold on... my dad's Captain?!
《いよいよだ　黒ツチと一緒に
有利にもっていく》
It's finally time!
SECOND COMPANY CAPTAIN:
KITSUCHI
With Kurotsuchi beside me,
I'll turn the tide of battle!
（リー）大丈夫ですか　ガイ先生！
Are you all right, Guy Sensei?
（サクラ）まだ戦争前なんですけど
何やったんです？
The fighting hasn't started!
What did you do?
THIRD COMPANY:
INTERMEDIATE-RANGE BATTLE UNIT
THIRD COMPANY CAPTAIN:
HATAKE KAKASHI
（チョウジ）今のうちに
食いだめしとかないと。
I'd better eat while I still can!
FOURTH COMPANY:
LONG-RANGE BATTLE UNIT
（テマリ）我愛羅が
うちら第４部隊長だが→
Gaara is the captain of
our Fourth Company,
あいつは　連隊長でもある。
but he's also
the commander-in-chief.
代理だが　実質は
お前が第４部隊長だ。
As his deputy, you're essentially
the captain of the Fourth Company.
しっかりな。
Stay sharp!
（シカマル）めんどくせえとこに
配属されちまったぜ　ったくよ。
What a bothersome assignment!
COMMANDER-IN-CHIEF AND
FOURTH COMPANY CAPTAIN: GAARA
（キバ）この戦争でひと旗あげて
火影にでもなってやるか！
Maybe I'll make a name for myself
in this war and become the Hokage!
FIFTH COMPANY:
SPECIAL BATTLE UNIT
（ハナ）バカ…
戦争をなめるんじゃない！
You fool...
Don't make light of war!
（シノ）目立つ行動は避けねば。
（いの）あんたは大丈夫よ　シノ…。
We have to avoid showing off.
You don't have to worry
about that, Shino...
FIFTH COMPANY CAPTAIN:
MIFUNE
（カカシ）さて…　我愛羅君。
君がこの大連隊の隊長だ。
Now then, Gaara.
You are the commander-in-chief.
落ち着いたら
ひと言頼むよ。
Please address everyone
when you're ready.
it's infinite, it's infinite, it's infinite, rock assault
eien desu eien desu eien desu totsugeki rock
I was asleep all this time, I kept quiet all this time
zutto nemutteta zutto damatteta
hey, it's calling us, hey, let's go
ooi yonde iru ooi itte mi yo
I can see something far away
tooku ni nanika ga mieru
something more important now than studying
benkyou yori mo ima taisetsu na mono
hey, it's calling us, hey, let's go
ooi yonde iru ooi itte mi yo
I think we can find it
mitsukarisou nanda
it's infinite, it's infinite, it's infinite, rock assault
eien desu eien desu eien desu totsugeki rock
see, you can overtake the future
mirai wa hora oinuite
this ship can really fly through the sky
hontou wa sora toberu fune
For My Friend
（トクマ）動いた！
それもかなりの数だぞ！
They're on the move!
And there's a large
amount of them.
（アンコ）あなたたちは
すぐに本隊と合流し　このことを。
Join up with the main forces
and inform them of this!
私は　残ってこのまま
アジトの探索をやる。
I will remain here and
investigate the hideout!
しかし　１人では危険すぎます！
It's too dangerous by yourself!
うるさい！　いいから行け！
Quiet! Just go!
危険は承知！
しかし　この情報を伝えねば→
I'm aware of the risks!
But if we don't get word to them,
仲間たちは
もっと危険になるんだぞ！
our comrades will be
in greater danger!
♪～
（白）再不再さん。
（再不再）あぁ…。
Zabuza...
I know...
This isn't the next plane.
ここは　あの世じゃなさそうだ。
意識は
はっきりしてるのに→
I'm totally conscious,
yet my body is moving on its own.
体は勝手に動いてる。
（ガリ）こりゃ禁術…　穢土転生だ。
This is the Forbidden Jutsu...
the Reanimation Jutsu.
俺たちは
何者かによって→
Someone summoned us
back to this world.
またこっちの世界へ
呼び戻されたってことだ。
つまり　これから戦うことになる。
It means we're going to be
fighting from now on.
死人まで利用するか…。
Someone's taking advantage
of dead people, eh...
そんな野郎に利用されるとは
気にくわねえ。
I don't like being used
by any such person!
（カブト）お前たちは奇襲陽動小隊。
空から行け！
You will be our Commando Unit.
Go by air!
（カブト）
サソリとデイダラは　トラップ爆破と敵襲。
Sasori and Deidara will lay traps
and conduct enemy raids.
霧の中吉と
木ノ葉の根は　感知とサポート。
Chukichi of the Hidden Mist and
the Leaf Foundation Ninja,
your job will be sensory intel
and support.
（シン）何だ　これは…。
What is... this?
（中吉）お前ら　暁だな。
You guys are with the Akatsuki.
言っとくが　お前らの好きに
こっちが動くと思っ…。
Let me make this clear.
If you try to control us...
（サソリ）こんなヘロヘロの
モヤシ野郎に利用されるとは→
If Akatsuki has to rely on a wimp
like that to order us around,
暁も地に落ちたな…。
they sure have fallen
on hard times.
しかも　生き残ってんのがゼツと
俺の後釜のトビってやつだけか…。
Not only that, the only survivor
is Zetsu and Tobi,
the one who replaced me...
（デイダラ）永久の美が　芸術だとか
のたまってたくせに→
You're quite brash for
being dead my good man.
死んだ旦那が
偉そうに言うなっての…　うん。
And you used to insist that
eternal beauty is art... Hmmm!
だいたい　あんなでかい弱点→
And it's all because
of that humongous
胸にくっつけてっからだ
うん！
weak spot stuck
on your chest, hmm!
デイダラ…　お前　殺されてえのか！
Deidara, do you want me
to kill you?
だから　もう死んでんだよ
旦那もおいらも　うん。
I'm already dead.
And so are you, hmm.
（マダラ）こんなんで
本当に大丈夫なのか？
Is this really going to work?
あまりに穢土転生の数が多くて
コントロールするには少々　大変でね。
There are too many
reanimated shinobi
and it's difficult to
control them all.
今は移動に集中して
コントロールしているだけだ。
Right now, I'm just focusing
on the mobilization.
最終的には僕が　すべて仕切る。
Ultimately,
I will direct everything.
戦闘になったときは人格を消し
殺戮人形になる。
When the fighting begins,
I will erase their personalities
and turn them into
killing machines.
心配いらない
まぁ　キャラを見てだけど。
There's no need to worry.
Of course, it will depend
on their characteristics.
そうしないほうが
いい場合もある。
Sometimes, it's better
not to change them.
感情を残せば敵の乱れが生じる
そこを突く。
Leaving their sentiments intact
will cause the enemy turmoil...
We'll aim for that weakness.
（アスマ）あなたはダンさんじゃ！？
Aren't you Master Dan?
（ダン）あぁ　俺たちの共通点は
死人ってことだ。
Yes...
What we share in common
is that we're dead.
生きた人間を生け贄に
死者の魂を呼び寄せる→
We have been resurrected
by a Forbidden Jutsu...
summoned to inhabit
the bodies of living sacrifices.
禁術にかけられている。
（ヒザシ）いったい　何があったんだ？
What is going on anyway?
嫌な予感がする。
I have a bad feeling...
白黒ゼツは連れて行かないのか？
Aren't you taking
Two-toned Zetsu?
ゼツはサスケの見張り役として
置いて行く。
I'm leaving Zetsu to keep
an eye on Sasuke.
戦争の隙に　お前に連れて
行かれんとも限らんからな。
I wouldn't put it past you
to look for the chance
to take him away
during the battle.
ふっ。
白ゼツ１０万は地中を走らせる。
I'm having the 100,000 White Zetsu
travel underground...
大軍が　ぞろぞろ動いたのでは
目立ちすぎる。
Such a large army would
only attract attention.
♪～
なら僕たちも出発しよう
さて　まずは…。
Then we shall set out too.
Now then, first...
《ムタ：すみません　アンコ隊長。
Forgive us, Captain Anko!
どうか無事でいてください！》
Please stay alive!
《この感じ　大蛇丸！？
いや　違う》
This sensation...
is it Orochimaru?!
No, it's not!
（２人）潜影多蛇手！
– Multiple Striking Shadow Snakes!
呪印をもらった程度で
大蛇丸様気取りかい。
Just because you
have a Curse Mark,
you think you're like
Lord Orochimaru, Anko Mitarashi!
みたらしアンコ。
貴様こそ主に代わったつもりか。
I could say the same about you!
Have you taken over as
the leader, Kabuto Yakushi?!
薬師カブト！
インテリの体術が私に通用するか！
Taijutsu from a bookworm
will not work on me!
Wha—?!
まともに体術で
やりあう気なんてないんだよ。
I have no intention of
fighting you with taijutsu.
僕はインテリなんでね。
I'm a bookworm.
《ど　毒？
あらゆる耐性を持つ私に…》
Poison? Me?
With all the antibodies that I have?
フフフ…　今や主は
僕のほうだってことさ。
So who is the lord now?
大蛇丸様の作り出した
毒の耐性では→
The antibody that
Lord Orochimaru developed
その毒は防げないよ。
will not work against
this poison.
あそこだ。
It's... over... there...
やっぱり　カブトの言ったとおりだ。
Kabuto was right.
２時の方向…　３匹　発見！
At two o'clock... I see three.
（ムタ）どうした！？
What's wrong?
ムタ！　ランカ！
お前たちは　そのまま走れ！
Muta! Ranka!
You two, hurry on!
ここは　俺が足止めする！
I will stall them!
情報を！
本隊に　情報を伝えるのだ！
The intel!
Get the intel to Headquarters!
連隊長が　あんな若造で
大丈夫なのか？
Can a young man manage as
the Commander-in-Chief?
我愛羅様は
そのへんの若造とは違う！
Lord Gaara is not your
average young man!
何も知らぬくせして
勝手なこと言うな！
How dare you make such
ignorant assumptions!
フン！　知るわけねえだろ！
つい　この間まで→
How am I supposed to know?
Until recently,
we were on opposite sides!
対立してた
やつらのことなんてな。
こっちもだ！
Right back at you!
まだ　お前たちのことを
信用しているわけではない。
It's not like we trust you either!
口の利き方に　気をつけろ！
So watch what you say!
（ホヘト）正直　俺だって　そうだ。
（ザジ）ウス！
To be honest,
I feel the same way.
Right!
って…
えっ？　今　なんて？　ホヘトさん。
Huh?
What did you just say, Hoheto?
大蛇丸に　騙されていたとはいえ→
Even if Orochimaru
deceived them,
砂は　木ノ葉崩しの
首謀者みたいなもんだ。
the Sand were behind the plot
to crush the Hidden Leaf.
あいつらがいなければ
ヒルゼン様は…！
If it weren't for them,
Lord Hiruzen would still...
や…　やだな～。
Look... We were lucky enough to
be named to the Commando Unit...
せっかく　エリートの奇襲部隊に
配属されたってのに…。
これからじゃないっすか！
Things are just about to start...
わかってる！　俺だって　忍だ。
I know that! I'm a shinobi too!
国や里が決めたことに
反対するつもりはない。
I'm not about to oppose what
our nation and village
have decided...
あくまで　個人の気持を
言えばということだ。
That was just
my personal opinion!
（タンゴ）木ノ葉が
偉そうに言ってんじゃねえよ！
You Hidden Leaf
don't have the right...
キラービー様を襲ったのも
五影会談を襲ったのも→
A rogue ninja from the Hidden Leaf
attacked Lord Killer Bee,
as well as the Five Hokage
at their summit!
木ノ葉の抜け忍じゃねえか！
雷影様が左手を失った責任を
とれるっていうのかよ！
Are you willing to
take responsibility
for the loss of
Lord Raikage's left hand?
なにっ！？
What?!
みんな　まだ　お互いを
信用しきれてないみたい。
No one completely trusts
each other yet.
（ネジ）しかたないことだ。
It can't be helped.
長年
対立してきたやつらを相手に→
After years on opposing sides,
昨日　今日で団結するのは難しい。
you can't expect them
to bond in a day or two.
特に　砂と岩はな。
Especially the Sand
and the Stone.
この野郎！
てめえ！
– Why you—!
– You jerk!
（キリ）フン…　これだから岩隠れは…。
That's why the Hidden Stone are...
（イッタン）おい　霧隠れの！
今　なんつった？
Hey you from the Hidden Mist!
What did you just say?
聞こえてたなら
しかたありませんね。
Since you overheard me,
what the hell.
あなたたち　岩隠れは→
I said that the Hidden Stone are
ruffians who ignore protocol!
礼儀をわきまえない
無礼者だって言ったんですよ。
んだと～！？
俺たち　霧隠れは→
What did you say?
We have not forgotten
the Hidden Stone's treachery
ヨスガ峠の悲劇を…→
岩隠れの裏切りを
忘れたわけじゃない！
in the Tragedy of Yosuga Pass!
ヨスガ峠？
Yosuga Pass?
ずいぶん　古い話を
持ち出すじゃねえか。
You're bringing up ancient history.
１人　牢の中で…→
We agreed to this unit's formation
to honor Ganryu,
平和を望む
巌流さんの意志を汲めばこそ→
who wished for peace
from his solitary prison.
この部隊編成にも　うなずいた。
♪～
だが　やはり
霧と岩が手を組むなど　ありえん！
But the Mist and Stone
can never become allies!
木ノ葉の野郎！
やる気か　雲隠れ！
You Leaf bastard!
Want to do something about it,
Hidden Cloud?!
どうせ　また
裏切るつもりだろう　岩隠れ！
You're gonna betray us
again anyway, right, Hidden Stone?
霧は　口だけか？
文句があるなら　拳でこい！
Are the Mist just all talk?
If you have a complaint,
say it with your fists!
言葉に　気をつけるのは
お前のほうだ！
You're the one who needs to
watch what he says!
なんだと！？　やんのか！
あぁ！
What?!
Wanna fight?
俺の親父は
お前たち砂に殺された！
Sure! You Sand killed my father!
ここで
殺してやっても　いいんだぞ！
I'd be glad to kill you right here!
おい　やめろ！
Hey, stop!
はぁ～。
♪～
Huh?!
（我愛羅）自国自里の
利益のために…。
In the name of gain and profit
for one's nation and village...
第一次から　第三次までの
長きに亘り→
Shinobi have hated and hurt
each other for many years,
忍は　お互いを傷つけ
憎しみ合ってきた。
from the First to the Third
Great Ninja Wars.
その憎しみは　力を欲し
俺が生まれた。
That hatred cried out for power,
and thus, I was born.
かつて　俺も憎しみであり
力であり　人柱力であった。
In the past, I too was
hatred and power...
I was a Jinchuriki.
そして　この世界と人間を憎み
滅ぼそうと考えた。
And I hated this world
and the humans in it
and thought about
destroying them.
今　暁がなそうとしていることと
同じだ。
This is exactly what the Akatsuki
is trying to do now.
だが　木ノ葉の一人の忍が
それを止めてくれた！
However... a single shinobi from
the Hidden Leaf stopped me.
((ナルト：お前の気持は→
I know how you feel so well...
I know it hurts.
なんでかな？
痛いほどわかるんだってばよ。
我愛羅。
Gaara...
ナルト…。
Naruto...
(世話かけやがって))
Putting us through
all this trouble!
♪～
その者は　敵である
俺のために泣いてくれた。
He cried for me, his enemy!
傷つけた俺を
友だと言ってくれた！
We wounded each other in battle
but he called me his friend!
彼は　俺を救った。
He saved me!
敵どうしだったが
彼は　同じ　人柱力だった。
We were enemies,
but we were both Jinchuriki...
同じ痛みを理解し合った者どうし
わだかまりは　ない！
When we share and
experience the same pain,
there can be no bad blood!
今　ここに敵はいない！
No one is an enemy here!
なぜなら　皆…　暁に傷つけられた
痛みを持っている！
Because we all bear the pain of
having been hurt by the Akatsuki.
砂も…。
The Sand...
岩も…。
The Stone...
木ノ葉も…。
The Leaf...
霧も…。
The Mist...
雲もない！
The Cloud are no more!
あるのは　ただ→
Now, there is only...
忍だ！
...shinobi!
もし　それでも
砂が許せないのなら→
If you still cannot
forgive the Sand,
この戦争のあとに
俺の首をはねればいい！
after this war is over,
you can have my head!
《みんなの顔つきが変わった…》
The look in everyone's faces
has changed.
俺を救ってくれた　その友を→
The enemy is now after
my friend who saved me!
今　敵は狙っている！
彼が敵に渡れば　世界は終わる！
If he falls into enemy hands,
this world is finished!
俺は　友を守りたい！
I want to protect my friend!
そして　この世界を守りたい！！
And I want to protect this world!
世界を守るには　俺は若すぎる…
浅すぎる！
But I am much too young,
too inexperienced to
protect this world!
だから…
みんなの力を貸してくれ！
So I beg you all to
lend me your strength!
もちろんだ　我愛羅様～！
You got it, Lord Gaara!
さっきは　すまなかった…。
Sorry about that...
あぁ…　俺も悪かったよ。
No... I was wrong too.
（タンゴ）すまん…　言い過ぎた。
Sorry... I said too much.
俺のほうこそ　すまなかった。
I apologize too.
（キリ）が…　巌流さん！？　どうして…。
Ganryu! How did you?
（巌流）同じ痛みを持つ忍が
ひとつになろうってときだ。
It's time for all
shinobi who have
felt the same pain
to come together.
わだかまりを持たないのならば
協力してくれとさ。
I was told that my help
would be welcome,
if I held no grudges.
こんな俺の力ですら
必要な戦いになるってことさ。
It means this war
is so important that
they'll accept help from
even someone like me.
俺たちは　同じ忍…。
だな…。
We are all one shinobi...
ここは　ひとつになって
暁をぶっ潰そうぜ！
Yeah. Let's be one and
beat some Akatsuki!
あぁ！
うむ！
Damn right!
Uh-uh!
《カンクロウ：
強い熱を持った連中ほど→
The more passionate they are,
まとまったときは
強くなるじゃん…。
the stronger the bond
that is forged...
なあ　我愛羅》
Right, Gaara?
（マツリ）きゃ～！　さすが　我愛羅様！
You have to hand it
to Lord Gaara!
（ユカタ）我愛羅様…。
Lord Gaara!
《立派になったな…　我愛羅》
You've become
a fine man... Gaara!
これで　みんな
仲間になれたってわけか。
So now, we're all comrades.
めんどくせえけど
仲間のニオイじゃ→
It's a nuisance, but I guess we
have to learn all their scents!
覚えねえわけには　いかねえなぁ！
犬塚家の鼻にかけてね。
The reputation of
the Inuzuka nose is on the line.
同意するものは　俺に続け～！！
All who feel as I do!
Follow me!
うぉ～！！
やったってばよ！
I did it!
（キラービー）やるじゃねえか。
Not bad.
なら　これから最後の修業…。
Next up is the final lesson.
寂しくて　やるせない
だが　やるぜ。
Sad, but true,
it's hard to proceed...
But we must move forward
with the deed.
♪～
BACKUP MEDICAL UNIT
SENSORY UNIT
COMMANDO UNIT
（エー）第四次忍界大戦…
我々が勝つ！
The Fourth Great Ninja War...
We will win!
（オオノキ）当たり前じゃぜ！
（綱手）ああ！
That goes without saying!
《俺たちは　一丸となって→
We will!
We will unite as one and
fight until our last breath...
命尽きるまで戦おう。
友と世界のために！》
for the sake of our friend
and this world!
♪～
you and I held hands tightly and a light was born
kimi to boku nigirishimeta futatsu no te no naka de
let's release it now
umareta hikari ima hanatou
the town, tinged amber by the sunset
kohaku iro no yuuyake ni somerareta
projects a sad light and shadow
machi wa kanashii hikari to kage utsushite ita
I've encountered and gotten tangled
ikutsu mono kiseki no ito
in so many miraculous threads
tsunagatte karamatte tadoritsuita yo
it all starts here and now
hajimeru no wa ima kono basho kara
it'll clear up after the rain, become that cloud
ame nochi hare ano kumo ni nare
and swim towards the present
ima wo oyoi de yuku
toss away the hesitation
sono kokoro shibaritsuketeru
that clings to your heart
tamerai furihodoite
you and I held hands
kimi to boku nigirishimeta
and deep inside
futatsu no te no naka de
is the eternal proof of you
kieru koto nai kimi no akashi
with our liberated hands
jiyuu na sono ryoute de
let's start again, from here
koko kara mata hajimeyou
Next Episode
We're already in enemy territory.
皆様　お変わりございませんか？
Omoi! Go set Paper Bomb traps.
Sai, you'll be on aerial surveillance.
美空ひばりです。
では最後まで　ごゆっくり→
Ittan, use Earth Style to make a trench.
お楽しみください。
Tango, set up a Chakra Communication antenna!
Zaji and Hoheto! You two will be on sensory and watch duty.
（宮本）『木曜８時のコンサート
名曲！　にっぽんの歌』。
Next time on Naruto Shippuden: War Begins
War Begins
（松丸）今回は　ご覧の
豪華歌手９組の皆さんによる→
This is war. Never let your guard down.
Tune in again!